<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications and working paper | Marina</title>
    <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications and working paper</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Publications and working paper</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gender Quotas and Support for Women in Board Elections</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/board_quota/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/board_quota/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:0px;&#34;&gt;Presentations (selected)&amp;#58; SEA 2022, Conference on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion in Economics, Finance, and Central Banking 2022, Discrimination and Diversity Workshop 2023, ECBE 2023, AEA 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:0px;&#34;&gt;How did &amp;#35;MeToo alter the cost of collaboration between women and men? I show junior female academics start fewer projects after &amp;#35;MeToo. A decrease in collaborations with new male co-authors at the same institution largely explains the decline in projects. The decrease is more pronounced when sexual harassment policies are less clear, in universities with more (public) incidents of sexual harassment, and when amended Title IX regulations (2020) are less favorable towards the accused. This is consistent with men managing a higher perceived risk of sexual harassment accusations as a potential explanation for the decrease in collaborations. Overall, &amp;#35;MeToo appears to bring unintended consequences that impact the career opportunities of junior women. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:0px; color:navy;&#34;&gt;Note&amp;#58; While I have not pre-registered the study, I am providing the access to the original time-stamped (unsuccessful) grant proposal for this study (dated June, 9 2021).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;figure2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

Overview of coefficients on the post dummy from a regression where the dependent variable is the number of new projects started with different co-author types in a given year by a junior female academic (N=393).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unintended Consequences of MeToo Evidence from Research Collaborations</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/metoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/metoo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:0px;&#34;&gt;Presentations (selected)&amp;#58; SEA 2022, Conference on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion in Economics, Finance, and Central Banking 2022, Discrimination and Diversity Workshop 2023, ECBE 2023, AEA 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:0px;&#34;&gt;How did &amp;#35;MeToo alter the cost of collaboration between women and men? I show junior female academics start fewer projects after &amp;#35;MeToo. A decrease in collaborations with new male co-authors at the same institution largely explains the decline in projects. The decrease is more pronounced when sexual harassment policies are less clear, in universities with more (public) incidents of sexual harassment, and when amended Title IX regulations (2020) are less favorable towards the accused. This is consistent with men managing a higher perceived risk of sexual harassment accusations as a potential explanation for the decrease in collaborations. Overall, &amp;#35;MeToo appears to bring unintended consequences that impact the career opportunities of junior women. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:0px; color:navy;&#34;&gt;Note&amp;#58; While I have not pre-registered the study, I am providing the access to the original time-stamped (unsuccessful) grant proposal for this study (dated June, 9 2021).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /research/metoo/figure2_hucbb1fc0cb29a3a8a8ed3b3b2014c76d7_330558_97956ac92cce30491ebcd184de67c898.webp 400w,
               /research/metoo/figure2_hucbb1fc0cb29a3a8a8ed3b3b2014c76d7_330558_861dccf34bdd35e2cc7ab33eec47317f.webp 760w,
               /research/metoo/figure2_hucbb1fc0cb29a3a8a8ed3b3b2014c76d7_330558_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/metoo/figure2_hucbb1fc0cb29a3a8a8ed3b3b2014c76d7_330558_97956ac92cce30491ebcd184de67c898.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;475&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

Overview of coefficients on the post dummy from a regression where the dependent variable is the number of new projects started with different co-author types in a given year by a junior female academic (N=393).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Wants to Move First?</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/first_move/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/first_move/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regulatory Fragmentation</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/fragmentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/fragmentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;color:darkred; text-align:center; font-weight:bold; font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Revise and Resubmit, The Journal of Finance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://marinagertsberg.github.io/data/fragmentation&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;font-size:20px;&#34;&gt;We make the data collected for this project publicly available. Check this page!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:center; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:0px;&#34;&gt;  Best paper award at FMARC conference &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:0px;&#34;&gt;  Presented at AFA, Future of Financial Information Conference, Financial Research Network (FIRN), APRCF Conference, Copenhagen Business School, the Federal Reserve, George Mason University, University of Rochester, Boston College, University of Toronto, University of Melbourne, University of Washington, Wayne State University, Florida International University, University of Bath, University of Bristol.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-size:16px; padding:10px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Regulatory fragmentation occurs when multiple federal agencies oversee a single issue. Using the full text of the Federal Register, the government’s official daily publication, we provide the first systematic evidence on the extent and costs of regulatory fragmentation. Fragmentation increases the firm’s costs while lowering its productivity, profitability, and growth. Moreover, it deters entry into an industry and increases the propensity of small firms to exit. These effects arise from redundancy and, more prominently, from inconsistencies between government agencies. Our results uncover a new source of regulatory burden, and we show that agency issues among regulators contribute to this burden.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Blockholder Diversity Detrimental?</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/blockholders/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/blockholders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;color:darkred; text-align:center; font-weight:bold; font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Revise and Resubmit, Management Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://marinagertsberg.github.io/data/blocks&#34; style=&#34;text-decoration: underline;font-size:20px;&#34;&gt;We make the data collected for this project publicly available. Check this page!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-style:italic; font-size:16px; padding:10px;&#34;&gt;
    Presented at the AFA, FMA, FIRN, Frontiers of Finance, QCFC, the Bank of Israel, IE HU Workshop, Ben Gurion University, Binghamton University, Cornell University, Copenhagen Business School, Emory University, the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, Higher School of Economics, University of Hong Kong, London Business School, University of Melbourne, Michigan State University, New Economic School, and the University of Technology Sydney
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-size:16px; padding:10px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; We find that blockholder diversity, i.e., the firm shareholder base including several different types of blocks, is detrimental to firm performance. We show that lagged disclosure, on exogenous predetermined dates, that reveals an increase in block diversity is followed by a negative market reaction. Firms held by heterogeneous blockholders consistently perform worse than firms held by homogeneous blockholders. Block diversity is particularly detrimental when uncertainty is high. Disagreement among shareholders (e.g., as reflected in the frequency of lawsuits being filed) increases when the blockholder base is diverse. We make our blockholder dataset public for the benefit of other researchers.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-size:16px; padding:10px; color:#000080;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Metaphorical Summary:&lt;/strong&gt; The image below is an illustration from a famous fable penned by the Russian poet Ivan Krylov, &#34;The Swan, the Crayfish, and the Pike.&#34; In this allegorical tale, three animals attempt to pull a wagon together. However, due to their distinct methods and conflicting directions - the swan flying upward, the crayfish crawling backward, and the pike diving into the water - they fail to move the wagon. This lack of coordination and cooperation exemplifies how a failure to align on common goals can lead to complete stagnation.
    &lt;br&gt;
    Similarly, in our paper, we explore the dynamics between large shareholders, or blockholders, of different types. Though these shareholders may aim to work in concert, diverging incentives and preferences often render their attempts counterproductive. This modern application of Krylov&#39;s timeless message underscores the critical importance of cohesion and aligned interests in the world of corporate finance.
&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /research/blockholders/krulov_hu106d1f73e8b374bc9ea5170480d22f86_409046_6e74e02ebf7d607a963ad8d05d74697e.webp 400w,
               /research/blockholders/krulov_hu106d1f73e8b374bc9ea5170480d22f86_409046_b20e4231093dd28b2598d0992c70e6d3.webp 760w,
               /research/blockholders/krulov_hu106d1f73e8b374bc9ea5170480d22f86_409046_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/blockholders/krulov_hu106d1f73e8b374bc9ea5170480d22f86_409046_6e74e02ebf7d607a963ad8d05d74697e.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;574&#34;
               height=&#34;704&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Appointing Charity Directors in Response to ESG Incidents</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/esg_directors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/esg_directors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-size:16px; padding:0px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; This paper examines how companies respond to negative ESG incidents by appointing directors with experience in charitable organizations. We find that firms are more likely to make such appointments following ESG incidents, especially when these incidents attract substantial media attention or involve social issues. The market responds positively to these appointments. We further provide evidence that firms genuinely leverage the expertise of charity directors to enhance their ESG performance, rather than appointing them for ESG window dressing. These directors are often assigned to committees overseeing ESG issues, and their appointments are associated with a higher likelihood of implementing ESG-linked compensation policies and a reduction in future incidents, particularly those related to community and workforce issues. This decrease in future incidents is primarily driven by non-overboarded directors. Overall, our findings emphasize the tangible value that charity-experienced directors bring to companies when they need to address ESG concerns.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Disciplining Effect of Status Evaluator Status Attainment and Observed Gender Bias in Evaluations</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/evalutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/evalutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;color:darkred; text-align:center; font-weight:bold; font-style:italic;&#34;&gt;Management Science (2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align:left; font-size:16px; padding:10px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; We theorize that status awards will have a disciplining effect on evaluators, changing how they evaluate. Specifically, status awards will lead evaluators to place less weight on unreliable indicators of candidate quality, such as gender. We test this theory using data from restaurant evaluations on Yelp, focusing on the relationship between an evaluator’s restaurant rating and their reporting of being served by a man or a woman in their review text. We use Yelp’s evaluator status award (“Elite”) to analyze whether observed gender bias in the star ratings given to restaurants decreases after an evaluator receives this status award. We find that evaluators rate restaurants more similarly after receiving the award, regardless of whether they report being served by a man or a woman. Status awards in our context close the gender gap in restaurant ratings by 56.5% (a 0.07 stars improvement out of an initial rating gap of −0.13 stars). This reduction in gender bias is mostly due to a decrease in the number of extremely low (1 star) ratings in reviews that reference female servers. Research on status and evaluations has mostly focused on how evaluators react to increases in candidate status. We demonstrate the importance of evaluator status as a mechanism for decreasing observed gender differences in evaluations.
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Public Offering A Synthesis of the Literature and Directions for Future Research</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/art_market_network/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/art_market_network/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Public Offering A Synthesis of the Literature and Directions for Future Research</title>
      <link>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/price_art_market/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://marinagertsberg.github.io/research/price_art_market/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
